If we want that the gateway can reach the network server, we need to configure it.
That was the first step of the Lorawan network configuration in the previous chapter.
The configuration depends on the packet forwarder we use, but basically the gateway needs to know the
IP address and port used by the network server.
And if we want that, this gateway has the right to talk to the network server.
We also need to register it.
That was the second step of the network configuration.
The internet connection between the gateway and the network server is called the backhaul connectivity.
It can rely on Ethernet, WiFi, 4G, LTE, and these are the most common.
It depends on the kind of connectivity you've bought with your gateway.
The LoRaWAN gateway is the key point of the transmission on one side.
On the left, it takes the lower radio signal.
And on the other side, it sends the demodulated information to the network server.
Thanks to an IP frame.
When the LoRa packet leaves the device and reaches the gateway, the gateway extract the content called
PHY payload.
Then this whole PHY payload is encapsulated in an IP frame and sent to the network server. In the IP
frame,
everything is transmitted as text, usually using a JSON object.
JSON is a simple way to transfer data as text format.
But what do we exactly find in this data?
First there is the PHY payload, as we said earlier.
This PHY  payload is transmitted as plaintext, but some part like the frame payload is encrypted. Anyway,
the gateway doesn't need the LoRaWAN information, so it usually doesn't check any of these fields.
But the PHY payload is not the only useful information, the network server also needs information about
radio transmission.
What was the RSI in the receiver?
The SNR, the spreading factor used, channel, bandwidth coding
rate.
That is something that the network server should know.
The user might be interested, but above all, the network server needs it to process the LoRaWAN
stack.
For example, the stack needs it for the computation of the best LoRaWAN parameters.
When we use the adaptive datarate algorithm.